{"test_questions": [[{"question": "For culturing, plasma from the adult chicken is preferred to mammalian plasma because", "opta": "it forms a clear and solid coagulum even after dilution", "optb": "it is too opaque", "optc": "it doesn't produce solid clots", "optd": "it forms a semi solid coagulum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Toxicity due to accumulation of ammonia can be overcome", "opta": "by substituting glutamine by glutamate", "optb": "by controlled addition of glutamine at low level", "optc": "by removal of ammonia or ammonium from culture medium", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Range of osmolarity tolerated/accepted in mOsm/Kg of H2O by mammalian cells is", "opta": "150-300", "optb": "280-360", "optc": "300-325", "optd": "360-400", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Disaggregating of cells can be achieved by", "opta": "physical disruption", "optb": "enzymatic digestion", "optc": "treating with chelating agents", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Accumulation of lactate leads to", "opta": "increase in pH", "optb": "no change in pH", "optc": "reduction in the pH of culture hence loss of cell viability", "optd": "no loss of cell viability", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When dissolved oxygen is lower than the critical concentration, viable cell concentration declines because of", "opta": "incomplete glutamine oxidation", "optb": "increase in specific lactate production from glucose", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "accumulation of ammonia", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to Eagle, the growth of L-strain and Hela-strain cultures require to have mandatory presence of", "opta": "6 amino acids", "optb": "8 amino acids", "optc": "10 amino acids", "optd": "12 amino acids", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Excess CO2 suppress cell growth and productivity by", "opta": "inhibiting respiration", "optb": "altering intracellular pH by diffusing across cell membrane", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "altering pH of the medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "opta": "Established cell lines (ECL) have short doubling time", "optb": "ECL are invariably aneuploid", "optc": "ECL grow in higher density", "optd": "ECL do not show much evidence of spatial orientation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the effect of excess accumulation of metabolite products (lactate and ammonium) on cells?", "opta": "They act as growth promoters", "optb": "They act as growth inhibitors", "optc": "Have no effect on cells", "optd": "Lactate helps in the growth while ammonium inhibits the growth", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the concentration of CO2 required for culturing animal cells?", "opta": "2-5%", "optb": "1-10%", "optc": "10-15%", "optd": "15-20%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "ECL can be established in suspension cultures whereas it is exceptional for primary cell lines (PCL)", "optb": "ECL and PCL can be established in suspension cultures", "optc": "PCL can be established in suspension cultures", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the followings are the metabolic products of glucose and glutamine?", "opta": "CO2 and NH3", "optb": "CO2 and lactate", "optc": "Lactate and ammonium", "optd": "Lactate only", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To prevent the accumulation of lactate", "opta": "low glutamine concentration is required", "optb": "high glutamine concentration is required", "optc": "low glucose concentration is required", "optd": "high glucose concentration is required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the main constituents of culture for animal cell growth?", "opta": "Glucose and Glutamine", "optb": "Growth factors", "optc": "Cytokines", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During the growth of animal cells in culture, it is noticed that the cells do not look very healthy. After an investigation, this is found that there is a lot of lactic acid in the culture fluid. What is probably wrong with this culture?", "opta": "Ethyl alcohol is being produced in excess", "optb": "The cells have too much oxygen", "optc": "Glycolysis is being inhibited", "optd": "The cells do not have enough oxygen", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Range of optimum glutamine concentration present in the culture media is", "opta": "1-2 mmol/litre", "optb": "2-7 mmol/litre", "optc": "7-15 mmol/litre", "optd": "15 - 20 mmol/litre", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The human fibroplast is a classical example of", "opta": "stable primary cell lines", "optb": "established cell lines", "optc": "cell transformations", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "pH of culture medium is initially controlled by", "opta": "presence of CO2", "optb": "presence of bicarbonate buffer", "optc": "addition of bases", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following abnormality, resulted from the inheritance of an unbalanced complement of chromosomes can be diagnosed through karotyping?", "opta": "Down's syndrome", "optb": "Turner's syndrome", "optc": "Klinefelter's syndrome", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In animal cell culture, particularly mammalian cell culture, transformation means", "opta": "uptake of new genetic material", "optb": "phenotypic modifications of cells in culture", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "release of genetic information", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How does CO2 help in the cell metabolism during cell culture?", "opta": "It participates in the de novo synthesis of purines and pyrimidines", "optb": "Helps in the cells respiration", "optc": "For monitoring pH of the culture", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not the explantation technique?", "opta": "Slide culture", "optb": "Carrel flask culture", "optc": "Roller test tube culture", "optd": "Adherent primary culture", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cells which have undergone transformation frequently become", "opta": "anchorage independent", "optb": "anchorage dependent", "optc": "stable", "optd": "unstable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Range of optimum glucose concentration present in the culture media is", "opta": "5.5 - 55 mmol/litre", "optb": "55 - 75 mmol/litre", "optc": "75-105 mmol/litre", "optd": "105-150 mmol/litre", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique of organ culture may be divided on the basis of employing", "opta": "solid medium", "optb": "liquid medium", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "semi-solid medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At low glucose concentration, below 0.25 mmol/litre, large portions of glucose and glutamine is shunted via", "opta": "oxidative pathway", "optb": "anaerobic pathway", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An established cell line can be called where it has been subcultured at least", "opta": "70 times at an interval of 3 days between subcultures", "optb": "40 times at an interval of 3 days between subcultures", "optc": "70 times at an interval of 1 day between subcultures", "optd": "50 times at an interval of 3 days between subcultures", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Specific oxygen consumption rates for mammalian cells are in the range of (where n and p represents to nano and pico respectively)", "opta": "0.05-5 nmol of O2/cell/h", "optb": "5 - 10 nmol of O2 /cell/h", "optc": "0.05-5 pmol of O2/cell/h", "optd": "5 - 10 pmol of O2/cell/h", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a source of energy in active muscle cells?", "opta": "Creatine phosphate", "optb": "ATP", "optc": "Lactic acid", "optd": "Glucose", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sometimes cell lines can be cultured for such a long time that they apparently develop the potential to be subcultured indefinitely in vitro. Such cells lines are called", "opta": "established cell lines", "optb": "primary cell lines", "optc": "secondary cell lines", "optd": "propagated cell lines", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Higher dissolved oxygen concentration in the culture media are toxic and lead to", "opta": "DNA degradation", "optb": "lipid peroxidation", "optc": "metabolism of nutrients in culture media at a rate greater than that required for consumption", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the technique used for the embryo culture?", "opta": "Organ cultures on plasma clots", "optb": "Organ cultures on agar", "optc": "Whole embryo cultures", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major problem associated with the isolation of free cells and cell aggregates from organs is that of", "opta": "releasing the cells from their supporting matrix", "optb": "inhibiting the cells from their supporting matrix", "optc": "disintegrating the cells from their supporting matrix", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}